Today on Polar Ice Creamy we're going to do
a really quick easy vanilla ice cream using
extract or vanilla bean or vanilla bean paste,
condensed milk, cream, milk and that's it,
nothing else.... so four ingredients
total, let's get on and make it [Music]
First off, yes I just walked in from the gym
but I really wanted to get this ice cream
made quickly so I can actually eat some while
the house is empty and enjoy all to myself.
So a really easy recipe, we're going to make a
super luxury vanilla ice cream with milk, cream,
condensed milk and your choice of vanilla.
Four ingredients! I've got a vanilla bean,
homemade vanilla extract, homemade vanilla bean
paste, use whatever one you want. I'm going
to say if you're going to use the vanilla bean
then you're going to need to warm your milk up
with your split bean in and just let it sit for
half an hour okay and that's to make sure that
that vanilla flavor is infused into your milk.
Okay we're not going to use the vanilla bean
this time so I'll put that over there ,we're not
going to use the extract, we're going to put that
over there, today we are going to use homemade
vanilla bean paste let me know in the comments
if you want to see how I make this. It's super
easy by the way. So let's get everything measured
up and we can get it right in the machine straight
away. So what are we going to need? nice and easy
milk, cream, let's just go we're going to
need 350g of milk which is 1 and 1/2 cups,
we're going to need exactly the same
amount of cream 350g (1 and 1/2 cups)
an entire 10 oz can (which is 300 ml) of
condensed milk. Sweetened condensed milk,
condensed milk it's all the same so we
don't want to lose any of that so there we
go get that whole thing in
there love me some condensed milk don't need
that and finally, vanilla
bean paste we going to add
four teaspoons of vanilla bean
paste, we want a nice strong
flavor so
and we are now just going to get this all
combined. Whisk it for a couple of minutes.
It's all whisked up, let's get this in the fridge
while we get our ice cream machine
out and up to down to temperature
This is going to take 10 minutes to come down
to temperature, we'll come back and churn it
Here we go, ice cream machine is nice and cold
we're just going to pour this
straight in here and get it
churning I want those seeds/caviar in
There, 20 minutes later we've
got gorgeous vanilla ice cream
let's get this in a container and get it in the
[Music]
freezer
four ingredient super simple vanilla ice cream, so
easy to make that you don't have to heat anything
you just have to mix all the ingredients together
using a really good quality vanilla or if you
can't get you know a really good brand just
use whatever you've got available. You want
this to be nice and strong and flavor so don't be
afraid of adding more, sometimes it's nice to have
a recipe that is really this simple. You know on
this channel I do some really complex ice creams,
this one just cuts through that nice and easy
you can make ice cream in the morning have it
ready for the end of the day you know you've got
a kids party, you've got people coming over, it's
Wednesday and you just want some ice cream at the
end without buying the absolute junk store-bought
stuff with 100% overun. This this made about 1.4
liters of ice cream in total from just over a
liters worth of ingredients, 1.1L so you know
we we're looking at 20 to 25% overun which is
perfect territory for a really good quality
ice cream anyway less chat more eat [Music]
There is nothing bad you can say about this,
it's not going to break any records for being,
you know, the most luxurious ice cream but what
you've got is the perfect amount of overrun,
really creamy texture, super easy to make,
quick, cheap and effective sometimes that is
just what we need for homemade ice cream. Give
this one a try now, nice and easy to do you can
change vanilla for any other extract going so
you could use this recipe for lemon, orange,
coffee, chocolate, hazelnut, the list goes on
so I hope you enjoyed this simplified video,
thanks very much for watching, don't forget to
like and subscribe and I will see you next time.